good morning thanks for coming this
早上好，谢谢你来这个
morning I know it's an early start but
早上我知道这是一个开始，但是
thanks for coming in today
谢谢你今天来
my name is Stewart Marx I work at Oracle
我叫Stewart Marx我在甲骨文工作
on the JDK work in the core libraries
JDK在核心库中的工作
team and one of the things I do is
团队，我要做的事情之一是
maintain the collections framework and
维护馆藏框架并
so the title of this talk is collections
所以这个演讲的题目是收藏
refueled so I'm going to be covering the
加油，所以我将覆盖
collections enhancements in JDK 9 and a
JDK 9和
little bit of a glimpse of what we might
一瞥我们可能会遇到的情况
be working on in the future so let's see
将来会继续工作，让我们看看
this is only a 45-minute session and so
这只是一个45分钟的课程，因此
I had to trim this down from an hour I
我不得不从一个小时的时间里把它剪下来
might or might not have time for
可能或可能没有时间
questions at the end but if there's a
最后的问题，但如果有
question that you have that you don't
问题，你有没有
get a chance to ask me in the session
有机会在会议上问我
then please tweet on this hashtag
然后请在这个标签上发推文
collections refueled and I will try to
收藏加油，我会尽力
get to it after the after the session
会议结束后到达
alright so one slide on history of the
好吧，那么一张关于历史的幻灯片
collections framework so in JDK 1.0 in
集合框架，所以在JDK 1.0中
1996 there were there wasn't anything
1996那里什么都没有
called the collections fairmark there
在那里称为收藏集标记
were some collections there which we we
我们那里有一些藏品
now retrospectively call the legacy
现在回想起旧版
collections those are the classes like
这些是类似的集合
vector and hash table which you might
向量和哈希表，您可能会
remember I hope you're not using those
记得我希望你不要用那些
although I did see them in a stack trace
虽然我确实在堆栈跟踪中看到了它们
in the in the keynote yesterday hmm okay
在昨天的主题演讲中，嗯
so in jdk 1.2 now that was when the
所以在jdk 1.2中，现在是
collections framework was actually
收集框架实际上是
introduced so joshua bloch designed to
介绍了约书亚布洛赫
develop those and integrated those into
发展那些并将其整合到
the JDK back in 1998
1998年的JDK
so the collections framework is a little
所以收藏框架有点
bit younger than Java so it's about 19
比Java小一点，所以大约19岁
years old at this point and so that's
此时已经几岁了，所以
what introduced the set of interfaces
什么介绍了接口集
that we that were so familiar with
如此熟悉的我们
collection list set math and so forth
集合列表设置数学等
and also the collections that that
还有那个
probably everybody uses like ArrayList
可能每个人都使用像ArrayList
and hash map and so I don't have the
和哈希图，所以我没有
reference on my fingertips but there was
指尖上的参考，但有
some paper that did an empirical study
一些进行实证研究的论文
of of collection usage and ArrayList and
集合用法和ArrayList的集合，以及
hash map are by far the two most
哈希图是迄今为止最多的两个
frequently used collections in Java
Java中的常用集合
programs so it's pretty amazing now
程序，所以现在非常神奇
these these classes have been
这些课程是
reimplemented over the
重新实现
but the the basics of these classes were
但是这些课程的基础是
introduced nineteen years ago and
介绍于19年前，
there's still the most among the most
仍然是其中最多的
popular collection classes in use today
当今使用的流行收藏类
now the next big step up was in 2004
现在下一步是2004年
with Java SE 5 when generics were
当泛型为Java SE 5时
introduced and so as part of the
作为介绍的一部分
introduction of generics to the
将泛型介绍给
programming language the collection
编程语言集合
libraries were upgraded to be genera
图书馆升格为属
fide and so you got better type-checking
善意，所以您有更好的类型检查
when you put elements into and removed
当您将元素放入或移除时
elements from collections and in Java 8
集合和Java 8中的元素
the language was once again operated big
语言再次大受欢迎
upgrade to add lambda in the streams
升级以在流中添加lambda
library now the streams library is kind
库，现在流库很友好
of not officially part of the
不是官方的一部分
collections framework but basically it
收藏框架，但基本上
it the the most frequent stream source
它是最频繁的流源
and stream destination are collections
和流目标是集合
so the streams library works very
因此流库非常有效
closely with the collections framework
与馆藏框架紧密联系
but there's another language feature in
但是其中还有另一种语言功能
Java 8 which is default methods on
Java 8是默认方法
interfaces and so that got slipped in
接口，所以溜进去了
there you probably are familiar with
那里你可能很熟悉
that but one of the things that did was
那不过是做的一件事是
add a bunch of methods to those old
给那些旧的添加一堆方法
collection interfaces like collection
收集接口，如收集
list set math and so forth and so what
列表集数学等等，等等
that did is that had the effect of
那确实是有
enhancing every single existing
增强每一个现有的
collection even if that collection
即使该收藏
hadn't explicitly been upgraded to Java
没有明确升级到Java
8 the default methods really added a lot
8默认方法真的增加了很多
of power to the collections framework
收集框架的权力
without changing the collections
无需更改收藏
framework at all so it was actually very
框架，所以实际上
interesting enhancement now along the
现在有趣的增强
way there have been a few other classes
方式还有其他一些课程
added collections implementations added
添加了集合实现
here and there such as priority queue
在这里和那里，例如优先队列
and array deck and so forth but really
和阵列甲板等等，但实际上
these are the highlights of the history
这些是历史的亮点
of the collections framework up until
的收集框架直到
now alright so in Java 9 the main
现在好了，所以在Java 9中
enhancement to the collections framework
馆藏框架的增强
is called the convenience collection
被称为便利集合
collections convenience factory methods
集合便利工厂方法
so they're factory methods for creating
因此它们是工厂创建的方法
instances of new collections and so
新集合的实例等等
these are the three main goals here
这是这里的三个主要目标
convenience and brevity space efficiency
便捷空间效率
and unmodifiable 'ti so I'm going to go
和不可修改的'ti，所以我要去
through those in some detail
通过那些细节
all right so a bit of history here this
好吧，这里有一些历史
is a library only API and so a mark what
是仅库API，因此请注意
was this no this was actually in the ask
这是不是，这实际上是在问
the architects session yesterday so so
昨天的建筑师会议是如此
one of the things that other languages
其他语言之一
have is something called collection
有一个叫做收集的东西
literals and so there have been efforts
文字，所以一直在努力
to add collection literals to the java
将集合文字添加到java
programming language but there's some
编程语言，但有一些
problems so the way that Java is
问题，Java的方式
designed is the core aggregations if you
设计是核心汇总
want to aggregate certain data in the
想要汇总某些数据
java programming language you have
您拥有的Java编程语言
arrays which are built into the language
语言内置的数组
and you have classes which are built in
你有内置的类
a language you can add fields to a class
您可以在课程中添加字段的语言
and that's how you that's how you group
那就是你的方式那就是你的分组方式
unrelated data into into a higher-level
不相关的数据进入更高层次
construct that that creates a
创建一个
relationship between them but kind of
他们之间的关系，但那种
higher level abstractions like a set or
更高层次的抽象，例如集合或
or some higher level data structure is
或更高级的数据结构是
really delegated to the libraries in the
真正委托给了图书馆
way Java has been set up and so if you
Java的设置方式，如果您
created a language feature call that
创建了一个语言功能调用
that allowed you to write a that allowed
允许你写一个允许的
you to declare a collection in the
您在其中声明一个集合
programming language that would tie the
可以与
programming language to the library too
编程语言也到库
tightly and they're a bunch of design
紧密地，它们是一堆设计
issues that fell out of that but I don't
这样的问题，但我没有
have time to go into detail so you do
有时间详细介绍，所以您可以
something simple but that would be
一些简单的事情，但这将是
unsatisfactory if you wanted to avoid
如果您想避免，那就不能令人满意
that that solve the problems with that
那解决了那个问题
cause it turns out that it would get a
因为事实证明它将得到一个
lot more complex and so we set aside the
更加复杂，因此我们将
notion of adding collection literals to
将集合文字添加到的概念
the programming language and decided to
编程语言，并决定
focus on making collections easier to
专注于使收藏更容易
use using only library API construct all
仅使用库API构造所有
right and so here it is this is a quick
对，所以这是一个快速的过程
rundown of the the new API that were
新API的摘要
added in JDK 9 so there's a family of
是在JDK 9中添加的，因此
methods named of that have been added to
名为的方法已添加到
the list method these are static methods
列表方法是静态方法
on the list interface so list dot of
在列表界面上，所以列出
with 0 1 2 all the way up to
一直到0 1 2
ten arguments or there's also a varargs
十个参数，或者还有一个可变参数
version so you can pass an arbitrary
版本，因此您可以传递任意
number of elements to the list dot of
列表点的元素数
method no officially they're actually a
方法没有正式他们实际上是
let's see zero through ten plus VAR arc
让我们看一下零到十加VAR弧
so that's there are actually 12
所以实际上有12个
different overloads of list dot of but
但是列表点的不同重载
when you write the code it doesn't
当您编写代码时，它不会
actually matter you just say list dot of
其实你只说列表的点
and just a comma separated set of
只是逗号分隔的一组
elements and those get added to a newly
元素，并将这些元素添加到新
created list same thing with set dot
用设置点创建列表相同的东西
ah've there are a bunch of fixed arg
啊，有一堆固定的参数
overloads and VAR arg overloads but
重载和VAR arg重载，但
mainly just say set thought of and you
主要只是说定想而已
provide a comma separated list of the
提供以逗号分隔的列表
elements for the set now map thought of
现在考虑的集合元素映射
is a little bit different because unlike
有点不同，因为与众不同
set and list map has different types for
设置和列表映射具有不同的类型
the key and the value so what we did
关键和价值，所以我们做了什么
instead of was he said math dot of and
而不是他说和的数学点
then alternating key and value elements
然后交替键和值元素
now the problem there is that you if you
现在的问题是，如果你
have things of different types you
你有不同类型的东西
really can't have a varargs overload of
真的不能有varargs重载
that and make that work the same way so
并以相同的方式进行工作
instead what we had to do is if you want
相反，我们要做的就是如果您想要
to create a map with an arbitrary number
用任意数字创建地图
of elements you first have to box the
首先需要对元素进行装箱
key in the value into a map entry so we
将值键入地图条目，以便我们
added another we have added a static
添加了另一个，我们添加了一个静态
method called map entry it's a method as
称为地图输入的方法
distinct from the type mount dot capital
与类型安装点大写字母不同
entry and that takes the key in the
条目，并且需要输入密钥
value and puts them into an instance of
值并将其放入
math dot entry and then you have another
数学点输入，然后您有另一个
method mount dot of entries which takes
方法安装条目的点
a varargs
可变参数
list of those so you can create a map
这些列表，以便您可以创建地图
with an arbitrary number of pairs
有任意数量的对
alright so this is what it looks like in
好吧，这就是它的样子
the Javadoc so you can see all the
Javadoc，因此您可以看到所有
overloads there and it's amazing how
超载在那里，令人惊讶的是
people react to this when when this when
人们对此有何反应
this first got posted there was a
这个第一次被张贴有一个
discussion about this on reddit and
关于这个的讨论在reddit上
somebody said is this a joke but no this
有人说这是个玩笑，但不是这个
is not a joke but i think the main point
不是开玩笑，但我认为要点
here is this yeah this this is a certain
这是这个，这是一定的
amount of ugliness in the api but you do
api中的丑陋程度，但您确实
not see this ugliness when you program
编程时看不到这种丑陋
because you just see in the source code
因为你只在源代码中看到
what did I what did I use here math dot
我在这里用了什么数学点
of mapped out of or list out of or
的映射出或列表出或
whatever you just list the arguments and
无论您列出的参数是什么，
the fact that they are fixed Arg
他们是固定的Arg的事实
overloads and variable argument
重载和变量参数
overloads is immaterial to you except in
重载对您而言并不重要，除了
the in the math case and I'll show an
在数学案例中，我将显示一个
example of the map case later on but the
后面的地图案例示例，但
point here is that in in the library
这里的意思是在图书馆里
when we are developing the core
当我们开发核心
libraries and the collections framework
图书馆和馆藏框架
we're willing to take on some of this
我们愿意承担一些
ugliness so you don't have to so it
丑陋，所以您不必如此
really makes your code much more
确实使您的代码更多
convenient so let me show you some
方便，让我告诉你一些
examples of this in action so I think
这样的例子在行动，所以我认为
mark Reinhold might have demonstrated
马克·莱因霍尔德（Mark Reinhold）可能已经证明
some of this in the keynote yesterday
昨天主题演讲中的一些内容
but if you wanted to have an
但是如果您想拥有一个
unmodifiable list with a few elements
不可修改的清单，包含一些元素
you could you could wrap up those
你可以把那些包起来
elements in arrays not as lists and then
数组中的元素不是列表，然后
wrap wrap that and turn inside of
包裹包裹然后转到里面
collections on unmodifiable list and so
不可修改清单上的集合等
in Java dot 9 it's just list dot of ABC
在Java点9中，它只是ABC的列表点
that's really nice makes your code
这真的很不错，使您的代码
pretty compact I'm sorry I don't have to
非常紧凑，对不起，我不必
I don't have time for questions but if
我没有时间提问，但是如果
you're on Twitter please tweet and I'll
你在推特上发推文，我会
get back to you all right so with the
回到你身边，所以
set interface again there's something
再次设置界面
very similar now it's a little worse
非常相似，现在更糟
because you have to if you have certain
因为你必须
elements going into a set you have to
元素进入一组，你必须
take those elements and the only way to
采取这些要素和唯一途径
pass multiple elements to initialize a
传递多个元素以初始化
hat is to put them inside an array using
帽子是将它们放置在数组中
arrays dot as lists then put those
数组点作为列表，然后将那些
inside a hash set then put those inside
在哈希集内，然后将其放入
of an unmodifiable set and so once again
不可修改的集合，因此再次
it gets much more simple in JDK 9 you
它在JDK 9中变得更加简单
just say set dot of ABC alright so
只是说ABC的设定点好
here's here's where I have a slightly
这是我在这里稍微
different example from what Mark did in
与马克所做的例子不同
the keynote yesterday this is kind of a
昨天的主题演讲有点像
conventional way at the top of the slide
幻灯片顶部的常规方式
a conventional way to initialize a map
初始化地图的常规方法
just create the map empty and then call
只需将地图创建为空，然后调用
put on it several times
穿上几次
I think everybody's written this code
我想每个人都写了这段代码
they're variations of how to do that a
他们是如何做到这一点的变体
bunch of advantage that this manages but
这个管理的好处
this is the most straightforward way
这是最直接的方法
once you've finished adding things to
完成添加内容后
the map then you can wrap it in an
地图，然后您可以将其包装在
unmodifiable wrapper and so that's
不可修改的包装器，因此
pretty tedious and so here's where the
非常乏味，所以这是
big win is in Java nine I just say math
Java 9是我最大的胜利，我只是说数学
dot of a comma one B comma two C comma
逗号的点数一个B逗号两个C逗号
three and you can see here we're mixing
三个，你可以看到这里我们正在混合
types of string and int for the for the
的字符串和整数类型
key and the value now so this only works
键和现在的值，所以这仅适用
for up to ten key value pairs so if you
最多十个键值对，所以如果您
have more than ten key value pairs that
有十多个键值对
you want here's where we have to use
您想要这里是我们必须使用的地方
that that extra thing I was talking
我在说的那件事
about
关于
so the math dot entry static method so
所以数学点输入静态方法
here I kind of made up this type called
我在这里把这种类型称为
token type we have a map from string to
令牌类型，我们有一个从字符串到
token type and we want to have more than
令牌类型，我们希望拥有更多
ten entries there so there instead of
那里有十个条目
just having strings and token types side
仅具有字符串和令牌类型
by side we have to first wrap each one
并排，我们必须先包装每个
of those up into a map entry and then
那些进入地图条目，然后
pass all of those as varargs to a new
将所有这些作为varargs传递给新
method map dot of entries all right so
方法映射点的条目可以这样
so I just talked about the API but I
所以我刚刚谈到了API，但是我
haven't told you very much about what
并没有告诉你太多
gets returned from these api's now these
从这些api现在返回这些
the implementations that are returned by
返回的实现
these conform to the list set and map
这些符合列表集和映射
interfaces but there are different
接口，但有不同
implementations from what we've seen in
我们从中看到的实现
the past so you don't get a regular
过去，所以你不定期
array list or a hash map out of these so
其中的数组列表或哈希映射
they have quite a quite a number of
他们有很多
different characteristics from from the
从不同的特点
existing collection implementations so
现有的集合实现
in particular they are unmodifiable and
特别是它们是不可修改的，
there's well I'll go into all of these
好吧，我会介绍所有这些
in detail we disallowed nulls randomized
详细地说，我们不允许将null随机化
iteration or that's a big deal I'll try
迭代，否则我会尝试的
to spend some time on that we disallowed
花一些时间来禁止我们
duplicates in the list so probably it's
在列表中重复，所以可能是
a programming error if you if you put
如果你把编程错误
duplicates if you're listing out a bunch
如果您列出一堆，则重复
of elements explicit thing you have
元素的明确内容
duplicates for sets and maps I think a
我认为集合和地图重复
very interesting point is that they are
非常有趣的一点是，他们
much more space efficient than the
空间效率比
existing collections particularly hasha
现有的收藏，尤其是hasha
and there are some wrinkles to do with
而且有一些皱纹
serialization which I'll cover all right
序列化，我会介绍
so the new static factory methods all
所以所有新的静态工厂方法
returned collection instances that are
返回的集合实例是
unmodifiable and so by that we mean it's
不可修改，因此我们的意思是
the same old interface but and so you
相同的旧界面，但是等等
can say get or you can iterate over the
可以说得到或您可以遍历
collection or whatever as usual things
收藏品或其他日常用品
that read from the collection work
从收集工作中读取
exactly the same as they do with a
与他们做的完全一样
conventional conventional clock or the
常规常规时钟或
the existing collections however if you
现有的收藏，但是如果您
attempt to add or remove or set an
尝试添加或删除或设置
element in one of these collections it
这些集合之一中的元素
will throw an unmodified unsupported
将抛出未经修改的不受支持
operation exception and then it's very
操作异常，然后非常
similar to the behavior of the
类似于
collection you get when you wrap
包裹时获得的收藏
something with collections dot
有收藏点的东西
unmodifiable list or or map or something
不可修改的列表或地图或其他内容
like that so I've talked a lot about
这样，所以我谈论了很多
unmodified unmodified bility what good
不变能力不变能力有什么好处
is because G don't you don't you want to
是因为G难道你不想
create a data structure so that you can
创建一个数据结构，以便您可以
add and remove things to it well often
经常添加和删除内容
you do and in that case you probably
你这样做，在这种情况下，你可能
should continue to want use one of the
应该继续想使用其中一种
existing collection implementations but
现有的集合实现，但
it's actually very common case where you
实际上，这是非常常见的情况
want to initialize a collection from a
要初始化一个集合
known set of constant values and then
一组已知的常数值，然后
never touch it later on and so you could
以后再也不要触摸它，因此您可以
just make sure in your program that
只要确保在您的程序中
nothing ever modifies it later on and
以后再也没有修改
that and that would be fine but if
那，那会很好，但是如果
something modified it by accident then
然后偶然地修改了某些东西
that might be a source of subtle bugs so
这可能是一些细微错误的来源，因此
you might go the extra step of wrapping
您可能会采取额外的包装步骤
it in an unmodified will wrap ur and
它在未经修改的情况下会包裹您和
that would be helpful that would
那会有所帮助
probably be a thing we would recommend
可能是我们推荐的一件事
that you do in Java 8 and earlier but
在Java 8和更早版本中所做的
with these these new convenience
这些新的便利
factoring methods you get a none
无因式分解的方法
modifiable list automatically now if you
现在，如果您可以自动修改列表
want to pre initialize a a collection
要预初始化AA集合
with a set of elements that you might
与您可能会使用的一组元素
later want to modify or add to the these
以后想修改或添加到这些
collection factors they're still useful
收集因子仍然有用
as initializers for the existing
作为现有的初始化程序
collections so if you had if you wanted
所以如果有的话
to pre initialize something like like a
预初始化类似
hash set you could say new
哈希集，你可以说新
set with lists of ABC or something like
设置ABC列表或类似内容
that so even even if you want to modify
即使您要修改
something later on these are still
这些以后的东西仍然
useful for initializing the conventional
用于初始化常规
collections there are other there are
有其他收藏
other reasons too to use unmodifiable
其他原因也使用不可修改的
sets if you have a class that has an
设置是否有一个具有
internal data structure which is
内部数据结构是
represented by a collection I got a list
以收藏集为代表我有一个清单
of something and you have a getter that
的东西，你有一个吸气剂
that gets that list of something well
这样可以很好地列出清单
you could just hand out the list but
您可以分发清单，但是
that would let the caller modify your
这将使呼叫者修改您的
internal data structures which is
内部数据结构是
probably not what you want to do and so
可能不是您想做的，所以
again you could be very careful and make
再次，你可能会非常小心，使
sure that none of your callers ever
确保没有任何来电者
modified that but if by accident or
修改了它，但是如果是偶然或
malice actually unfortunately we have to
不幸的是，我们不得不
think about that the caller decided to
考虑到呼叫者决定
modify the list that was returned then
修改然后返回的列表
that would create some subtle bugs or
会产生一些细微的错误或
even security holes so a class can
甚至安全漏洞，所以一堂课可以
protect itself if it has a unmodified
如果未修改，请保护自己
has a collection that's using internally
有一个在内部使用的收藏
it can wrap that in an unmodified little
可以将其包装在未修改的小包装中
wrapper and then pass it to the caller
包装器，然后将其传递给调用方
which is then prohibited from modifying
然后禁止修改
it so with the new collection factories
新的收藏工厂也是如此
you kind of get that for free so if you
您可以免费获得，所以如果您
pre initialize a data structure it's
预初始化一个数据结构
unmodifiable already and so you can just
已经无法修改，因此您可以
hand it out with impunity and you know
有罪不罚地分发出去，你知道
that nobody else can modify it and
没有其他人可以修改它，
corrupt your internal data structures so
破坏您的内部数据结构，因此
there's another aspect of a collection
还有另一个方面
being unmodifiable which is that the the
不可修改的是
the conventional collections like hash
像hash这样的常规集合
map are geared towards general-purpose
地图面向通用
operations including updates and so they
操作，包括更新，所以他们
have to handle a bunch of different
必须处理一堆不同的东西
cases that an unmodifiable collection
不可修改集合的情况
does not so on the implementation of an
并没有执行
unmodifiable collection is actually can
不可修改的收藏实际上是可以的
actually be quite a bit simpler than one
实际上比一个简单得多
of the conventional ones since it never
的传统，因为它从来没有
has to be modified so in particular the
必须进行修改，因此特别是
implementations we have in JDK 9 are
我们在JDK 9中的实现是
packed much more tightly because wait
打包得更紧密，因为等待
once once something lands in a certain
一旦某物降落在某个地方
place it never needs to move and it
放置它永远不需要移动的地方
never needs to be replaced so we just
永远不需要更换，所以我们只是
don't have
没有
to worry about that case so we can take
担心这种情况，所以我们可以采取
advantage of that and make the data
的优势，使数据
structure much more compact and also the
结构更加紧凑，而且
the code complexity is is much reduced
代码复杂度大大降低
so so there is a distinction here though
所以这里有一个区别
between the unmodifiable wrappers like
在不可修改的包装之间
collections dot unmodifiable list and
集合点不可修改的列表和
the unmodifiable collection you get from
您无法获得的收藏
list dot of so in the first actually
在第一个实际上列出so的点
actually i'll cover that on the next
其实我会在下一个介绍
slide so so here so I'm talking about
滑动所以在这里所以我在说
the unmodifiable list wrapper versus
不可修改的列表包装器与
list thought of so so let's take this
列出了想法，所以让我们来考虑一下
real simple code example here we have we
真正的简单代码示例在这里，我们有
have a list inner which consists of
有一个内部列表，包含
integers 1 2 &amp; 3 now we create 1 list
整数1 2＆3现在我们创建1个列表
which is an unmodifiable list wrapper
这是一个不可修改的列表包装器
around that list and then you create a
围绕该列表，然后创建一个
second list which is list dot of 1 2 3
第二个列表，即1 2 3的列表点
now what's the difference between those
现在那些之间有什么区别
well first let's talk about what's the
好吧，首先让我们谈谈什么是
same so you can certainly read from both
一样，所以您当然可以从两者中读取
of those you can do get you can do even
这些你可以做到的甚至可以做到的
you can do for each loop over them and
您可以为它们的每个循环做
so forth however if you attempt to call
依此类推，如果您尝试致电
add or call the set method both will
添加或调用set方法都将
throw unsupported operation exception so
抛出不受支持的操作异常，因此
in that sense they're both unmodifiable
从这个意义上说，它们都是不可修改的
that's why I'm using the same word
这就是为什么我使用相同的词
unmodifiable to describe both of those
不能描述两个
but there is a difference which is that
但有一个区别是
list 1 is an unmodifiable view of the
清单1是
other list which i've called inner here
我在这里称为内部的其他列表
now so so it's actually a bit subtle the
现在，所以实际上有点微妙
list named inner actually is modifiable
名为inner的列表实际上是可修改的
you can say inner dot set inner dot set
你可以说内点集内点集
0 17 it'll actually it'll actually
0 17实际上它将实际上
change that value there so it's it's
在那里改变那个值就是
actually a common point of confusion is
实际上，一个常见的混淆点是
that people often think that the the
人们常常认为
list return from arrays dot as list is
列表从数组点返回，列表为
is unmodifiable or even i've even heard
无法修改，甚至我都听不到
it called immutable that's not correct
它称为不可变是不正确的
you can actually change
你实际上可以改变
the elements in that set although you
虽然你在那个集合中的元素
cannot change its size which which gives
无法更改其大小，这给了
people which I think leads to that
我认为导致这种情况的人
confusion but anyway so so back to the
混乱，但无论如何还是回到了
wrapper though if you have lists one as
包装器，但如果您列出一个作为
a wrapper around the inner list so if
内部列表周围的包装器，如果
you change the contents of the inner
你改变内在的内容
list then list one can see those changes
列出然后列出一个可以看到那些更改
so if you have a reference to list one
因此，如果您有参考列出一个
you can iterate through it and look at
您可以遍历它并查看
those and then some some other piece of
那些，然后是其他一些
your code changes the inner list and if
您的代码会更改内部列表，如果
you iterate over list one again its
您再次遍历列表
contents are different now you can call
内容有所不同，您现在可以致电
methods on list one and you cannot
列出一个方法，您将无法
modify it so that's why we call this an
修改它，这就是为什么我们称其为
unmodifiable view so it has a view of
无法修改的视图，因此它具有
some other collection which might be
其他一些可能是
modifiable but you can't modify things
可修改的，但是你不能修改
through this view and so so the
通过这种观点等等
unmodifiable views have have existed in
存在不可修改的观点
in in the JDK for quite a long time I
我在JDK中工作了很长时间
think going all the way back perhaps to
想一路回到也许
one point to now what's new is that in
到现在有一​​点是新的
JDK 9 we have these new collections that
JDK 9中有这些新集合
are themselves unmodifiable they're not
本身是不可修改的，它们不是
a view of something else so list 2
其他观点，请列出2
contains the elements itself and it's
包含元素本身，它是
unmodifiable so there's no other
无法修改，因此没有其他
collection floating around somewhere
集合漂浮在某个地方
that could be modified that this is a
可以修改为这是一个
view of Solus dot 2 is the list itself
Solus点2的视图是列表本身
and it is unmodifiable so you if you
它是不可修改的，所以如果您
look at other materials on the web that
看网上的其他资料
that I've produced previous talks I've
我已经做过以前的演讲
said I've used the term immutable to
说我用了不可变
describe these collections and I've
描述这些收藏，我已经
moved away from that I think I deserve
离开了我认为我应该得到的
to give you a little bit of an
给你一点
explanation for that you there's a lot
解释你有很多
of material out there on the web that
网上的资料
other people have written we just copied
别人写了我们刚刚抄写的
me that have called these immutable
称这些不变的我
collections and list2 is in fact
集合和list2实际上
immutable but only because its contents
不可变，但仅因为其内容
are immutable so these get boxed into
是不可变的，所以将它们装箱
java.lang integer classes which are
java.lang整数类是
immutable so if you have immutable
一成不变，所以如果你有一成不变
objects inside an unmodifiable
不可修改的对象
collection the whole thing is immutable
收集整个事情是一成不变的
but imagine if you took some string
但是想像一下你是否带了一些弦
buffer instances and said list out of
缓冲区实例和表示出来的列表
ring buffer one string buffer two string
环形缓冲区一个字符串缓冲区两个字符串
buffer three you can modify those string
缓冲区三可以修改那些字符串
buffers so in in no sense is list not of
缓冲，所以在任何情况下列表都不是
returning an immutable collection
返回一个不可变的集合
because everything in it is modifiable
因为其中的所有内容都是可修改的
so really so that's the explanation for
所以真的，这就是对
why I've started to steer the
为什么我开始转向
terminology over to unmodifiable so we
术语变得无法修改，因此我们
say that the collection is unmodifiable
说收藏是不可修改的
and that's a completely separate
那是完全分开的
statement from any statement you might
您可能会发表的任何陈述中的陈述
make about the contents of the
弄清楚
collection okay so moving on so one one
收集还可以，所以继续前进一个
design decision we made was to disallow
我们所做的设计决定是不允许
nulls
空值
in the new collection instances so if
在新的集合实例中，如果
you attempt to say list out of one
你试图说出一个清单
common all comma three or something like
常见的全逗号三或类似的东西
that it'll throw a nullpointerexception
它会抛出一个nullpointerexception
so I in retrospect if you if you look at
所以我回想一下，如果你看
the collections that were introduced
引进的收藏
originally in JDK 1.2 they did allow
最初在JDK 1.2中，他们确实允许
nulls so you can put nulls in ArrayList
空值，因此您可以将空值放在ArrayList中
you can put nulls in hashmap but it
您可以将null放入hashmap中，但是
turns out that no other collection
原来没有其他收藏
supports that well very few other
支持得很好
collections do in fact most of the
实际上，大多数收藏
collections that were introduced after
之后介绍的收藏
one point two do not support nulls none
一分二不支持空无
of the collections in java.util
java.util中的集合
concurrent support nulls and there's
并发支持为空，并且
there's a reason for that well one is
有一个原因是
null as bad we've probably I should
null为坏，我们可能应该
probably give an entire talk about null
可能会完整地谈论null
at some point
在某一点
although we do have to talk about
虽然我们必须谈论
optional on Thursday which is closely
周四是可选的
related but there's but there's another
相关，但有另一个
reason which is that nulls make things
原因是空使事情
hard to program so if you look at the
很难编程，所以如果你看
map dot get method you pass it a key and
映射点的get方法，您将其传递给密钥，
it returns the value corresponding to
它返回对应于的值
that key well what happens if that key
那把钥匙好吧，如果那把钥匙会发生什么
is not present in the map well it
不在地图上很好吗
returns null okay now what if in that
返回null好吧，如果在那
map in a hash map that key is actually
在哈希图中映射该键实际上是
mapped to the value null it also returns
映射到null值，它也会返回
null so if you say map get and you get a
null，所以如果您说map get并且您得到一个
null back you don't know whether the key
返回null，你不知道键是否
was present or absent and that's a
存在或不存在，那是一个
fundamental ambiguity that arises from
产生的根本歧义
allowing null and
允许null和
as an actual value instead of using it
作为实际值而不是使用它
as a sentinel which it actually is so so
作为一个哨兵，实际上是如此
that occurs in several places in the API
在API中的多个位置发生
where it's hard to tell whether no means
很难分辨是否没有办法
well the actual value is null or there
实际值是null还是那里
is no value so that's a fundamental
没有价值，所以这是一个根本
problem with semantics of no also no is
否否的语义问题是
very very useful inside of
内部非常非常有用
implementations as a sentinel value so
实现作为定点值，因此
the the collections implementations we
我们的集合实现
have use null to mean there is no
使用null表示没有
element here and so if you look at the
元素在这里，所以如果你看
set implementation it uses closed
设置它使用封闭的实现
hashing in a single array so it's very
散列在单个数组中，因此非常
compact but null means the absence of an
紧凑但为null表示不存在
entry so searching can stop at that
条目，因此搜索可以从此停止
point
点
so there's no possible if well we can
所以我们不可能
only do that if we disallow no as of an
只有在我们不允许任何情况下才这样做
actual value that can be present in the
可以存在于
set or in the map okay moving on to two
设置或在地图上可以继续到两个
other issues randomized the iteration
其他问题随机化迭代
order so this is a this is a bit of a
订单，所以这是一个这有点
controversy so if you look at the
争议，所以如果你看
history of most most of the collections
大多数收藏的历史
particularly basically the hash based
特别是基本上基于哈希
one so if you look at hash map for
因此，如果您查看哈希图
instance if you read the specification
实例，如果您阅读规范
carefully it says the elements if you
仔细地说，如果你
iterate over the entries of a hash map
遍历哈希映射的条目
you will get the elements in no
你会得到没有的元素
particular order and the problem is that
特定的顺序，问题是
the order actually was quite predictable
订单实际上是可以预见的
even though it was not specified and
即使未指定
even worse most often in hash map the
更糟糕的是，在哈希图中
oft-used key type in hash map is string
哈希映射中经常使用的键类型是字符串
and strings have a notoriously bad hash
和字符串有一个众所周知的坏哈希
code so if you put a bunch of strings in
代码，如果您在其中放入一串字符串
they'll actually and and if you put a
他们实际上会，如果您放一个
bunch of strings into a hash set or hash
一串字符串变成一个哈希集或哈希
map and then iterate over them they'll
映射，然后遍历它们，他们将
actually come out in sorted order and so
实际上是按排序顺序出来的，所以
the problem is if you start to depend on
问题是，如果您开始依赖
that order and then somebody adds
该命令，然后有人添加
another value that which you weren't
你不是的另一个价值
expecting and causes the the hash map to
期望并导致哈希映射
to rehash itself and put things in
重新整理自己并将其放入
different buckets then that order
那个顺序就不同了
changes and it might break your code
更改，可能会破坏您的代码
now maybe you've you you might have
现在也许你有你可能有
designed your code to be more resilient
将代码设计得更具弹性
to that but actually in in practice what
为此，但实际上在实践中
happens is that once a hashmap is loaded
发生的是，一旦加载了哈希图
with something it tends not to change
有些东西往往不会改变
that much so what happens is the code
如此多的是代码
tends to build up an implicit dependency
倾向于建立隐式依赖
on the iteration order of the keys of a
在一个键的迭代顺序上
hash map now the other problem is that
哈希图现在另一个问题是
from time to time in the JDK we change
在JDK中，我们有时会更改
the iteration order of a hash map right
哈希图的迭代顺序正确
the specification says they're not
规范说他们不是
returned in any particular order so we
以任何特定顺序返回，因此我们
might change the iteration order of a
可能会更改
hash map in order to optimize things or
哈希图以优化事物或
in order to protect against security
为了防止安全
vulnerabilities and so forth and this
漏洞等等
does happen from time to time with the
确实会不时发生
frequency of JDK releases being fairly
JDK发布的频率相当
low this didn't happen very often and in
低，这种情况并不经常发生
fact it happened with about the worst
事实上发生的最糟糕
possible frequency it would happen so we
可能发生的频率，所以我们
released a JDK a bunch of code would be
发布了JDK，一堆代码将是
written that depended on the hashmap
取决于哈希图的书面内容
order in this version of the JDK years
订购此版本的JDK
later we'd change the iteration order of
稍后，我们将更改
hash map and then it would break
哈希图，然后它将打破
everything and so there would be a bunch
一切，所以会有一堆
of complaints about it and you know
关于它的投诉，你知道
maybe rightly you know you can only get
也许对，你知道你只能得到
so far by saying I'm sorry if you read
到目前为止，对不起，如果您阅读
the spec your code is wrong you'd have
您的代码规范错误
to go fix it right
去纠正它
that gets tiresome after a while it gets
一段时间后变得很累
tiresome for everybody and so and the
大家都很累，所以
problem is and and and and it seeped
问题是and和and而且渗入
it's very easy to say you guys need to
很难说你们需要
fix your code and so I don't want to say
修复您的代码，所以我不想说
that because our code has the same
因为我们的代码具有相同的
problem we had a we had a bug in the
我们有一个问题，我们有一个错误
compiler that was due to the exact same
完全相同的编译器
thing and it was mystifying and so we
事情，这是令人迷惑的，所以我们
said you know let's change that to a
说你知道让我们将其更改为
linked hash map and the problem went
链接的哈希图和问题去了
away so it's clear there's a there's a
走了，所以很明显有一个
very serious problem which is code all
非常严重的问题是全部代码
too easily depends on implicit ordering
太容易依赖于隐式排序
in a hash map so that's all introduction
在哈希图中，这就是所有介绍
to what we're doing here with the new
我们在这里用新的
collection implementations of set and
set和set的collection实现
math in JDK 9 the iteration order is
在JDK 9中，数学的迭代顺序为
randomized so at the start when it when
随机，所以在开始的时候
it when the JVM starts it cups up comes
它在JVM启动时启动
up with hash seed and uses that as part
哈希种子并将其用作一部分
of the hash computation
哈希计算的
so from one run to the next the
所以从一个运行到下一个
iteration order of a set or map that you
您所设置的集合或映射的迭代顺序
get from these new api's is is going to
从这些新的api获取将
be different so you might say oh oh my
不一样，所以你可能会说哦，哦，我的
gosh this is gonna this is gonna this is
天哪，这将是这将是
gonna break my code yes I wanted to
要破坏我的代码，是的，我想
break your code while you're developing
在开发时破坏代码
it and testing it so that way you you
并测试它，以便您
don't get broken when you upgrade to the
升级到
next version of the JDK so I think that
下一个版本的JDK，我认为
the the the principle here is that the
这里的原理是
specification allows the implementation
规范允许实施
to change but we made this sort of
改变，但我们做了这样的
implicit promise with hashmap not to
带有哈希图的隐式承诺不会
change it very often and I think that
经常更改它，我认为
was a mistake
是个错误
and so what we're doing here is we have
所以我们在这里要做的是
the same promise which is the elements
相同的承诺是要素
are returned in no particular order but
没有特别的顺序返回，但是
we were going to change it pretty
我们将要对其进行漂亮的更改
frequently to make sure that code that
经常确保该代码
uses this is resilient to changing of
使用它可以适应变化
iteration order and I'm hoping that
迭代顺序，我希望
everybody has a continuous integration
每个人都在不断融合
system that runs the tests frequently
经常运行测试的系统
that'll flush out these bugs before
会先清除这些错误
before they reach production now there's
在他们投入生产之前，
there's also an investment here too
这里也有投资
which is that we may want to change the
这就是我们可能想要更改
organization of these new set and map
这些新场景和地图的组织
implementations and so now if we believe
实施，所以现在，如果我们相信
that the code that's using these is
使用这些的代码是
resilient to changes in iteration order
适应迭代顺序的变化
we can completely rewrite this data
我们可以完全重写此数据
structure to make it even more compact
结构使其更加紧凑
or more efficient or something like that
或更有效的或类似的东西
and if that changes the iteration order
如果这改变了迭代顺序
doesn't matter because all the code out
没关系，因为所有代码都出来了
there is already resilient to whatever
已经有适应任何事物的能力
iteration order that that it's presented
呈现的迭代顺序
in now if you are still worried about
现在，如果您仍然担心
iteration order then first the existing
迭代顺序，然后先存在
implementations like hash map and hash
哈希映射和哈希之类的实现
that are not changing however there's
并没有改变，但是有
still a possibility in the future
将来仍有可能
release of the JDK we might need to make
我们可能需要发布JDK
a change that that does change the
确实改变了
iteration order if that is a problem
迭代顺序（如果有问题）
then you should use linked hash map
那么你应该使用链接的哈希图
because that guarantees a particular
因为那保证了特殊
iteration order or you can use something
迭代顺序，或者您可以使用某些东西
like a sorted map
就像一张排序的地图
that that also guarantees particular
那也保证了特别
order but there's some additional
点菜，但还有一些其他
expense having to do with that so but
与此相关的费用，但是
that's something to think about that has
那是要考虑的东西
has been a problem recurringly that that
一直是一个问题
hasn't gotten enough attention all right
还没有引起足够的重视
I covered most of this already I do want
我已经覆盖了我想要的大部分内容
to say that Java is not unique in this I
说Java在这方面不是唯一的
think other systems have have proceeded
认为其他系统已经进行
along the same lines in particular the
遵循相同的原则，特别是
go language has had math.random actually
语言已经有了math.random实际上
randomized iteration order since day one
从第一天开始随机迭代
I believe or at least since one point
我相信或至少从一点开始
now python is interesting it's gone back
现在python很有趣，它已经过去了
and forth in the Python 2x there was a
在Python 2x中有一个
single implementation of a dict and it
字典及其的单一实现
had some predictable iteration order
有一些可预测的迭代顺序
between versions 3.0 and 3.5 it was
在版本3.0和3.5之间
actually randomized 3.6 they got a new
实际上是随机的3.6他们得到了一个新的
implementation that was much better but
实施情况要好得多，但是
actually provides predictable iteration
实际上提供了可预测的迭代
order and so they have some you know
点餐，所以他们有一些你知道的
like us they've had some very long
像我们一样，他们经历了很长时间
discussions about whether randomization
关于是否随机化的讨论
was good or predictable iteration order
是好的或可预测的迭代顺序
was good it's actually it's interesting
很好，实际上很有趣
to watch those because I'm you know it's
看那些，因为我你知道
a completely different system from Java
与Java完全不同的系统
but they're having the same arguments so
但他们有相同的论据
again I want to reiterate that the
我再次重申
randomized iteration order applies only
随机迭代顺序仅适用
to the new collections that you get from
到您从中获得的新收藏
set thought of and math thought of so
设置思想和数学思想
the existing hashmap implementations are
现有的哈希图实现是
not changing as part of this all right
没有改变，这可以
so moving on so if you think about the
所以继续前进，如果您考虑一下
the the the origin of this feature was
该功能的起源是
in collection literals so the idea there
在集合文字中，所以那里的想法
is you want to declare a collection of
您是否要声明一个集合
some type and explicitly list out the
某种类型并明确列出
elements that would be in it so certain
其中的元素如此确定
things like well set and map again what
设置得好的东西，然后再映射一下
should be the behavior if you list the
如果您列出了应该是行为
same same element multiple times
多次相同同一元素
so if you're writing out the elements in
因此，如果您要写出其中的元素
the collection literal that's probably a
集合文字可能是
programming error now what what many
编程错误现在有多少
other systems do is they they apply some
其他系统所做的就是他们应用了一些
rule like last one wins and I think what
像上一个规则一样获胜，我认为
what that tends to do is is let subtle
倾向于做的是让它微妙
bugs creep into production so if you
虫子进入生产，所以如果您
have if you have a map actually yeah
有，如果你有地图，是的
there there are a couple other systems
还有其他几个系统
that that actually detect duplicates win
实际检测到重复的获胜
at initialization time but let me show
在初始化时，但让我展示
you an example here so this is a very
你这里的一个例子，这是一个非常
similar example to what I showed earlier
与我之前显示的例子类似
where you want to initialize a map with
您要在其中初始化地图的位置
a bunch of math entries now it turns out
现在发现了一堆数学条目
there's a duplicate in here and if you
这里有一个重复的，如果你
have sharp eyes you'll be able to spot
眼睛锐利，您将能够发现
it pretty quickly but there are a lot of
它很快，但是有很多
them and in if you are just initializing
他们，如果你只是在初始化
a map using the put calls then the the
使用put调用的地图，然后
later one would would would replace the
后来有人会取代
previous one and so you might I actually
前一个，所以你可能我实际上
don't know how many elements are how
不知道有多少元素
many entries there are in there maybe
那里有很多条目
they're twelve right so you might you
他们是十二岁，所以你可能会
might count the lines in here and say
可能会数一下这里的行数并说
there are twelve entries and then
有十二个条目，然后
there's some weird problem in production
生产中有一些奇怪的问题
and you go to debug yet and it's like
你去调试了，就像
huh this map has only eleven entries in
这张地图只有11个条目
it why is that and then you go back and
这是为什么，然后你回去
you stare at this and you might spot the
你盯着这个，你可能会发现
might might spot the problem immediately
可能会立即发现问题
or if it were like 1:30 in the morning
还是早上1点30分
because you got pulled out of your bed
因为你被下床了
by a pager call it might take you a long
通过寻呼机呼叫可能会花费您很长时间
time to see this and so so what we do
是时候看到这个了，所以我们该怎么做
instead is if you're listing out the
相反，如果您要列出
elements like this it's probably a
像这样的元素可能是
mistake if you have duplicate elements
如果您有重复的元素，则会出错
because what it means is that you put
因为这意味着你放
something in there that is actually
里面的东西实际上是
being ignored so what we do we can't
被忽略，所以我们不能做
catch that at compile time unfortunately
不幸的是在编译时发现了
ideally it would be but we do catch it
理想情况是这样，但我们确实抓住了它
at run time so as soon as map dot of
在运行时，只要
entries or map thought of tries to
试图进入的条目或地图
initialize a map with duplicate keys it
使用重复键初始化地图
will throw runtime exception and the
将抛出运行时异常，并且
same thing applies to set dot off
同样的情况也适用于关闭点
alright let me talk about space
好吧，让我谈谈太空
efficiency now so one thing you might
现在提高效率，所以您可能会做一件事
notice is that this is a departure from
注意，这是与
the from the API of the previous
来自先前的API
collection frameworks the the way that
收集框架的方式
that the collection framework existing
现有的收集框架
classes work is they would expose a
上课的工作是他们会暴露出
public class that was an implementation
实现的公共类
and there were there would be a variety
那里会有各种各样
of constructors for it so if you wanted
的建设者，所以如果你想
if you wanted a hash map you'd say new
如果您想要一个哈希图，您会说新的
hash map and then you could initialize
哈希图，然后您可以初始化
that with a size or you can initialize
具有大小或您可以初始化的
that from another map that would copy
来自另一张将复制的地图
the elements in and there are no public
里面没有公开的要素
class names for these new
这些新的类名
implementations and then that that's a
实现，然后就是
little difficult because it makes them
有点困难，因为这使他们
hard to talk about so I always have to
很难谈论，所以我总是不得不
say the collections implementation
说集合执行
returned by this nut off because because
被这个螺母掉了，因为
they have no names now obviously if you
他们现在显然没有名字，如果你
look in the source code they do have
查看他们确实拥有的源代码
names but but those names are not public
名称，但这些名称不是公开的
and there's a reason for that which is
这是有原因的
that preserves the freedom of the
保留了
implementers namely me to completely
实施者即我完全
reorganize things in the future in a
将来重新组织事情
fully binary compatible way so in
完全二进制兼容的方式
particular I'll tell you about the
特别是我会告诉你
implementation we have in place today
我们今天已经到位的实施
which is four sets and maps are actually
这是四组，实际上是地图
four four lists and sets and there's a
四个四个列表和集合，还有一个
slight variation of this for maps but
这对于地图略有变化，但
for listening sets the selection this
聆听设置选择
don't have an array at all so if you
根本没有数组，所以如果你
look at an ArrayList an ArrayList stores
看一个ArrayList存储的ArrayList
this element in an array which is a
数组中的此元素是
completely separate object inside even
甚至将物体完全分开
if you have one element it creates a
如果您有一个元素，它将创建一个
whole array for it and stores that one
整个数组并存储其中一个
element in there so since we know these
因为我们知道这些
chain these collections are never going
连锁这些收藏永远不会走
to be modified if you want a set that
要修改的话
contains one element then we just have a
包含一个元素，那么我们只有一个
particular implementation that that
特定的实现
contains that element in exactly one
恰好包含一个元素
field and so for special cases zero one
字段，因此对于特殊情况为零
and two we store the elements of the
和两个我们存储的元素
collection in a field there are actually
在一个领域中收集实际上
different classes that implement those
实现这些的不同类
now for more than two elements we go
现在对于两个以上的要素
ahead and create an array and of the
并创建一个数组和
right size and and populate it
正确的大小并填充它
but there's nothing magical about 0 1 &amp;
但是0 1并没有什么神奇的
2 you can't tell this by looking at the
2您无法通过查看
API you can only tell by if you use a
您只能通过以下方式判断API：
reflection or something to go in but the
反射或其他东西，但
benefit of course is that the the amount
好处当然是金额
of space required for storing these in
存储这些空间所需的空间
memory is much reduced compared to the
与
conventional collections and they're
常规收藏，它们是
less spread out in memory so the
较少分散在内存中，因此
locality of reference should be improved
参考的地方应该改善
so let's run through an example very
所以让我们来看一个例子
quickly here so let's say that we want
快速在这里，所以我们说我们想要
to have a set with two elements in it
有一个包含两个元素的集合
and store that in an unmodified map in
并将其存储在未修改的地图中
the conventional Java Java 8 fashion so
常规Java Java 8的流行方式
we create a new hash set which has three
我们创建一个新的哈希集，其中包含三个
buckets because we don't want it to
桶，因为我们不希望它
resize so it has to have three buckets
调整大小，因此必须有三个水桶
in order to store to two elements we add
为了存储两个元素，我们添加了
the two elements to it and then we wrap
这两个元素，然后我们包装
that in an unmodified ball wrapper
在未经修改的包装纸中
okay so let's count the objects that are
好吧，让我们计算一下
there
那里
there's the unmodifiable wrapper there's
有不可修改的包装
the hash set now it turns out that a
哈希集现在证明了
hash set is implemented in terms of a
哈希集是根据
hash map so a hash map sorry a hash set
哈希图，所以哈希图对不起哈希集
contains an instance of hash map so
包含哈希映射的实例，因此
that's our third object now a hash map
那是我们的第三个对象，现在是哈希图
has an array which is the table of
有一个数组是
entries and an array to another object
条目和另一个对象的数组
so that's four objects and then each
这是四个对象，然后每个
entry of the hash map is stored in a
哈希图的条目存储在
node object so now we have six objects
节点对象，所以现在我们有六个对象
and so here is a diagram of what that
所以这是一个图
looks like we have we have the set
看起来我们有我们有一套
reference pointing to the unmodifiable
指向不可修改的参考
wrapper at the hash set the hash map the
哈希处的包装器设置哈希图
table which is an array and then two
表是一个数组，然后是两个
node elements so that's that's your six
节点元素，那就是您的六个
that's your six objects no note I'm not
那是你的六个物体，不，我不是
talking about the the the contents or
谈论内容或
the payload itself right so I'm not
有效载荷本身正确，所以我不是
counting the strings and there's a
数弦，有一个
special there's a special value there
特别那里有一个特别的价值
when you for a hash map when when it's
当您获取哈希图时
implemented as part of a hash set I'm
作为哈希集的一部分实现
only counting the things the objects
只数事物的对象
that are created as overhead for the
被创建为
collection itself so there's six objects
收集本身，所以有六个对象
there alright so how much memory does
好吧，那么有多少内存
each object take so in a typical JVM
每个对象都在典型的JVM中使用
every object has a twelve byte object
每个对象都有一个十二字节的对象
header plus about four by
标头加上大约四个
for every object reference or int field
对于每个对象引用或int字段
or smaller smaller primitive field and
或更小的较小的原始字段，以及
so these aren't exact it depends on
所以这些不完全取决于
exactly what you're using what what your
正是您在使用什么
JVM configuration is but this is a
JVM配置是，但这是一个
ballpark estimate so it turns out with
球场估计，所以事实证明
six objects with with all of with all of
六个对象一起所有
other fields and so forth a set with an
其他领域，等等
unmodifiable set with two elements takes
具有两个元素的不可修改集合
152 bytes that's surprisingly large but
152个字节，令人惊讶地大，但是
we've lived with that for a long time
我们已经住了很长时间
and and amazingly it hasn't really been
而且令人惊讶的是，它实际上并没有
a problem until recently I'm not quite
直到最近我还是一个问题
sure why but this is this is gaining
确定为什么，但是这就是越来越多
currency which is that I think people
我认为人们的货币
are trying to pack more they're trying
正在尝试收拾更多他们正在尝试的东西
to get more efficiency out of their
以提高他们的效率
systems if you if you're running
系统，如果您正在运行
thousands of instances in a cloud then
然后在云中成千上万个实例
if if you're heaps are too large that
如果堆太大，那
means the number of instances you can
表示您可以执行的实例数
run on each physical node in the cloud
在云中的每个物理节点上运行
is reduced and so people are
减少，所以人们
concentrating on reducing their heap
专注于减少他们的堆
sizes and so forth so that's how this
大小等等，这就是这个
this issue has started to come up a lot
这个问题开始出现了很多
all right so let's compare this to the
好吧，让我们将其与
to the new implementation that's
到新的实现
returned by set dot of so the code here
由设置点返回，所以代码在这里
is we say set dot of foo bar so the
是说设置foo bar的点，所以
source code is nice and simpler but if
源代码很好，更简单，但是如果
you look at the objects that are created
您查看创建的对象
there's an internal implementation
有一个内部实现
called set two which is a set that has
称为第二集
exactly two elements which are stored in
正好存储在两个元素中
the field and so that only takes 20
该领域，所以只需要20
bytes so if you have if you have a data
字节，如果有的话
structure like this you can reduce your
这样的结构可以减少您的
space consumption from this is again
再次消耗空间
this is overhead you can reduce the
这是开销，您可以减少
overhead of storing these these data
存储这些数据的开销
items from 152 bytes to 20 bytes so we
项目从152字节到20字节，所以我们
think that's a really really useful
认为这真的非常有用
space optimization in particular the JDK
空间优化，尤其是JDK
itself has started to use these
本身已经开始使用这些
implementations as part of its internal
作为其内部一部分的实现
startup and as part of the internal data
启动并作为内部数据的一部分
structures for say the module system and
例如模块系统的结构和
those guys are pleased this punch with
那些家伙很高兴与
this not only does it make their source
这不仅使其来源
code nicer but it actually reduces the
代码更好，但实际上减少了
space that's consumed so we can we can
占用的空间，所以我们可以
deliver a JDK that has
提供一个具有
reduced heat consumption at at the
降低了
beginning of at the start of Maine it
从缅因州开始
actually uses well it's doing more work
实际上使用得很好，它可以做更多的工作
because of the module system but it's
因为模块系统，但是
it's less this is less and it would have
越少越少，它本来就有
if we had used conventional collections
如果我们使用传统收藏
alright a quick word on serialization
好吧，关于序列化的简短介绍
yes the elements are the the collection
是的，元素是集合
implementations returned from these
从这些返回的实现
methods are serializable people really
方法真的可以序列化
use serialization but we use a
使用序列化，但我们使用
serialization proxy mechanism to keep
保留序列化代理机制
those internal implementations hidden so
那些内部实现隐藏了
we can reimplementation remains
我们可以重新实现
compatible with itself I think the main
与我自己兼容的主要
thing the main takeaway is if you are
要点是如果你是
serializing existing collections like
序列化现有集合，例如
ArrayList or hashmap the those will that
ArrayList或hashmap那些将
those will continue I mean those are
这些将继续，我的意思是那些是
serializable they'll continue to work
可序列化，他们将继续工作
between JDK 8 and JDK 9
在JDK 8和JDK 9之间
however if you create instances of these
但是，如果您创建这些实例
new collections and serialize them they
新收藏并对其进行序列化
cannot be deserialized on JDK 8 and
不能在JDK 8和
earlier and so you think about it well
较早，所以您考虑得很好
these classes didn't exist on those
这些类不存在
early releases but if you have an
早期版本，但如果您有
environment where your serializing
您进行序列化的环境
things and going across different JVM
事情和跨不同的JVM
versions or JDK versions you probably
版本或您可能的JDK版本
should stay away from these until every
应该远离这些，直到每个
until every instance is up on JDK 9
直到每个实例都在JDK 9上启动
alright a quick word on some things that
在某些事情上可以简单地说一下
I'm working on for the next release JDK
我正在为下一个版本的JDK进行开发
10 no I guess it's actually called JDK
10不，我猜它实际上叫做JDK
18.3 now it's it's actually pretty
18.3现在很漂亮
difficult to create instances of these
很难创建这些实例
collections with arbitrary elements that
具有任意元素的集合
are computed if you list them out I
如果你把它们列出来的话
showed you the API is for doing that but
向您展示了API就是这样做的，但是
sometimes what you want to do is read
有时候你想做的就是阅读
them from somewhere or compute them from
从某个地方或从他们计算
somewhere and and get get a bunch of
某个地方，得到一堆
elements and then load them into an
元素，然后将它们加载到
unmodifiable collection and so i've
无法修改的收藏，所以我
proposed adding new copy of methods that
建议添加新的方法副本
will copy from an existing collection or
将从现有馆藏中复制或
map
地图
and then also at the end of a stream you
然后在视频流的结尾
might want to do with dream computation
可能想做梦的计算
and then dump the elements that come out
然后转储出来的元素
at the end of the stream into an
在流的末尾
unmodifiable collection so I've proposed
无法修改的收藏，所以我建议
a family of new collectors so again
一个新的收藏家家族
these are not in Java 9 unfortunately
不幸的是，这些都不在Java 9中
but they are proposed for the next
但建议在下一个
release which is there's going to be
发布将会有
some discussion about this but our
一些讨论，但是我们
working number is 18 point 3 so JDK 18.3
工作编号是18点3，所以JDK 18.3
these are proposed for alright quick
这些建议很快就好了
summary and then we might have time for
总结，然后我们可能有时间
one or two questions collect the
一两个问题收集
collections framework is 19 years old
收藏框架已经19岁了
and so it's almost as old as the rest of
所以它几乎和其余的一样古老
Java but it still has a lot of legs I
Java，但我仍然有很多地方
think it's very useful I believe
我认为这非常有用
everybody's using it today and so we're
今天每个人都在使用它，所以我们
continuing to enhance it and make it
继续增强并使其
more useful the highlight of JDK Nine's
JDK Nine的亮点更加有用
collections are the new collection
集合是新集合
factory methods which i've just met the
我刚刚遇到的工厂方法
past 45 minutes talking about and JDK 9
过去45分钟内谈论和JDK 9
is now shipping it was quite a quite a
现在发货了
pleasure to update this I've been giving
很高兴更新我一直给的
this talk for a year or so and now I can
这个演讲一年左右，现在我可以
say JDK 9 is really out there and you
说JDK 9真的在那里
can download from either open GT open
可以从任一打开的GT下载
JDK or from Oracle's Java website so you
JDK或来自Oracle的Java网站，因此您
can contact me on Twitter or you can use
可以在Twitter上与我联系，或者您可以使用
the hash tag in the upper right corner
右上角的hash标签
and you might have time for one or two
你可能有时间一两个
quick questions before we're out any
在我们出去之前快速提问
does anybody have any yes right there
有人在那里有吗
right okay so is that the question I can
好吧，那我可以
hear you but but we're running out of
听到您的声音，但我们快用完了
time so let me let me let me try to
时间，让我让我让我尝试
respond and then I can talk to you
回应，然后我可以和你谈谈
afterwards but the question was about
之后，但问题是关于
about the duplicate duplicate key
关于重复的重复密钥
behavior that does not apply to hash
不适用于哈希的行为
math hash map java.util hashmaps
数学哈希图java.util hashmaps
behavior is unchanged so the the
行为不变，因此
duplicate key is only for the new api's
重复密钥仅适用于新api
math dot of math dot of entries and yeah
数学点的数学点和是的
there's there's some controversy about
那里有一些争议
that but why don't we talk about this
那但是为什么我们不谈论这个
afterwards and I might be able to help
之后，我也许可以提供帮助
you with it
你与它
one more question
还有一个问题
okay so this question was about the
好吧，这个问题是关于
internal implementations why did I stop
内部实现我为什么停下来
at two fields instead of ten well so in
在两个字段而不是十个字段中
a sense it's arbitrary
感觉是任意的
I believe there's kind of an exponential
我相信这里有指数
decay of the number of elements in a set
一组元素数量的衰减
so the the space advantage you get from
因此您从中获得的空间优势
having five fields or ten feet yeah you
有五个田地或十英尺长，是的，你
know a specialized set implementation
知道专门的集合实现
that had fields for five elements would
具有五个元素的字段
be much less useful than one for say
比说的有用得多
zero one and two elements because you
零一个和两个元素，因为你
know sets with with more elements occur
知道出现更多元素的集合
less frequently but the you know as we
不太频繁，但您知道我们
gather more data we may come across some
收集更多的数据，我们可能会遇到一些
case where somebody says you know I use
有人说你知道我用的情况
sets with three elements all the time
始终设置三个元素
and we pay this extra cost for storing
我们为此支付了额外的存储费用
those in an array so we might add a
那些在数组中，所以我们可以添加一个
third a third set implementation for
第三，第三套实现
that or actually we might even go the
那或者实际上我们甚至可能去
other way there's some other reasons we
换句话说，还有其他一些原因
might want to reduce the number of
可能希望减少数量
classes because it affects JIT
类，因为它会影响JIT
compilation and in a particularly
特别是汇编
obscure fashion so the point is we can
晦涩的时尚，所以重点是我们可以
change the implementations completely
完全改变实现
transparently and and compatibly and so
透明，兼容等
your code doesn't have to change you
您的代码不必更改您
don't have to recompile and the API is
无需重新编译，API是
don't have to change either all right so
不必更改任何一个都可以
at that point we're out of time thanks
那时我们没时间了，谢谢
very much enjoy the copy
非常喜欢复制
[Applause]
[掌声]